How do you pay for things in a shop?
你在商店里如何付款呢？
Perhaps you like the tangible reliability of hard cash?
或许你喜欢现金那种实实在在的可靠性？
Maybe the financial flexibility of a credit card suits you better?
也许信用卡在财务方面的灵活性更合你心意？
Or perhaps you prefer the simple convenience of a smartphone?
又或者你更青睐智能手机带来的便利？
Whatever you use today, experts believe all these methods could soon become outdated.
无论你如今使用哪种支付方式，专家们认为所有这些方式很快都可能变得过时。
Instead, we will use our bodies: our eyes, our fingerprints, even our mere presence in the store.
取而代之的是，我们将利用自己的身体：我们的眼睛、指纹，甚至仅仅是我们出现在商店里。
In fact it's happening already.
事实上，这种情况已经在发生了。
Amazon are trialling stores which have no checkouts, where technology tracks the items you've taken from the shelves and deducts the total from your account when you leave the shop.
亚马逊正在试验没有收银台的商店，在那里，技术会追踪你从货架上拿走的商品，当你离开商店时，就会从你的账户中扣除总金额。
French supermarket Monoprix takes a different path: you choose your groceries and leave them with a human cashier.
法国的Monoprix超市采取了不同的方式：你挑选好食品杂货后交给人工收银员。
You then leave the shop while the cashier tallies up your bill, charges your account, and organises delivery to your home.
然后你离开商店，与此同时收银员会结算你的账单，从你的账户中扣款，并安排送货上门。
Amir Sajed, chief executive of Barclaycard, told the BBC that such new developments spell the end of the plastic credit card.
巴克莱信用卡公司的首席执行官阿米尔·萨杰德告诉英国广播公司，这样的新发展标志着塑料信用卡的结束。
Instead, wearable items such as rings, bracelets and keychains will carry chips that allow shoppers to "seamlessly shop, going between the web, an app or in store," he says.
他说，相反，诸如戒指、手镯和钥匙链之类的可穿戴物品将配备芯片，使购物者能够“在网络、应用程序或实体店之间无缝购物”。
And while all the above payment methods are underpinned by accounts held in traditional currencies, let's not forget the rise of alternatives such as Litecoin.
虽然上述所有支付方式都由传统货币开设的账户支持，但我们也不要忘记像莱特币这样的替代货币的兴起。
Such virtual currencies can rise in value very quickly, but are also susceptible to crashes and threats from hackers.
这类虚拟货币的价值可以迅速攀升，但也容易受到金融机构倒闭（或系统崩溃）和黑客威胁的影响。
Who knows, perhaps something totally new will take off that changes money as we know it?
谁知道呢，也许会有全新的事物流行起来，从而改变我们所熟知的货币形式？
One such possibility is explored in the movie In Time.
电影《时间规划局》就探讨了这样一种可能性。
It imagines a futuristic society in which the currency is time itself, where people trade the amount of time they have left to live.
它设想了一个未来社会，在这个社会中，货币就是时间本身，人们交易自己剩余的寿命时间。
Or perhaps we'd do better to wind back the clock to the simpler financial world of the barter economy.
又或许我们最好让时光倒流，回到以物易物的简单金融世界。
While the term conjures images of sacks of grain and herds of sheep being exchanged in ancient times, there are signs that bartering is making a comeback in today's world of modern technology.
虽然“以物易物”这个词会让人想到古代用一袋袋粮食和一群群羊进行交换的情景，但有迹象表明，在当今的现代科技世界中，以物易物正卷土重来。
Startup Let's Barter India has developed an app which facilitates the exchange of goods, and already has around 100,000 members.
印度的初创公司“让我们来以物易物”开发了一款促进商品交换的应用程序，目前已经拥有大约10万名会员。
Maybe the only thing we know for certain is that money will keep evolving.
也许我们唯一可以确定的是，货币将不断演变。